柯克：舰长日志，星历5630.7
KIRK: Captain's log, stardate 5630.7.
我们被派去把美杜莎的大使送回家
We have been assigned to convey the Medusans' ambassador back home.
虽然美杜莎人的思想是卓越的，但他们的外表却不是
While the Medusans' thoughts are sublime, their appearance is not.
他们进化成了无形的种族
They have evolved into a formless race,
太过丑陋，以至于任何人类
so utterly hideous that the sight of a Medusan
只要看一眼美杜莎人就会陷入彻底的疯狂
brings total madness to any human who sees one.
马维克先生，我是詹姆斯·柯克，舰长
Mr. Marvick. I am James Kirk, the captain.
你必须在美杜莎大使到来之前离开
You must leave before the Medusan ambassador arrives.
这是史波克先生，我的大副
This is Mr. Spock, my first officer.
你留下来也无妨，但另一位先生……
It's OK for you to remain, but this other gentleman...
斯科特，轮机长，叫我斯科提
Scott, chief engineer. Call me Scotty.
你有面罩吗？
Do you have the visor?
戴上它，瞥见美杜莎的人类会发疯
Wear it. Humans who glimpse Medusans go insane.
我会戴上的
I shall wear it.
我们不要让大使久等
Let's not keep the ambassador waiting.
你和斯科特先生会有很多共同点
You and Mr. Scott will have a great deal in common.
能见到企业号的设计师是一种荣幸
It's a privilege meeting a designer of the Enterprise.
联系行星运输机控制中心
Open a channel to the planet transporter control center.
通知大使和琼斯博士，我们已准备好让他们登机了
Inform the ambassador and Dr. Jones we're ready to beam them aboard.
通话完毕
Kirk out.
你确定这个面罩有用吗？
Are you sure this visor will work?
- 对瓦肯人有用  - 你那人类的一半呢？
- It is effective for Vulcans. - What about your human half?
我会控制住的
I shall keep it under control.
传送完成时通知我
Inform me when transport is complete.
欢迎登船，科洛斯大使，我是大副史波克
Welcome aboard, Ambassador Kollos. I am First Officer Spock.
我是琼斯博士
I am Dr. Jones.
大使很荣幸见到你，史波克先生
The ambassador is most honored to meet you, Mr. Spock.
柯克：宇宙，最后的边疆
KIRK: Space, the final frontier.
这些是星舰企业号的航程
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务：探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
寻找新生命和新文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇踏前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
- 柯克舰长，我们准备好了  - 乌乎拉，打开所有甲板的频道
- Captain Kirk, we are ready. - Uhura, open a channel to all decks.
- 打开了，长官  - 柯克呼叫所有船员
- Channel open, sir. - This is Kirk to all ship's personnel.
清场计划现已生效，立即清空通道
Clearance plan's now in effect. Clear passageways immediately.
大使将立即被护送到他的住处
The ambassador will be escorted to his quarters at once.
请允许我祝贺你与科洛斯大使一起工作
May I congratulate you on your assignment with Ambassador Kollos.
谢谢，但目前还不确定
Thank you. But it's not yet definite.
这将取决于我是否有能力
It will depend upon my ability to achieve
与大使建立心灵连接
a mind-link with the ambassador.
我相信你会发现这是一种迷人的体验
I'm sure you will find it a fascinating experience.
我不知道有人与美杜莎人建立了心灵连接
I wasn't aware anyone had achieved a mind-link with the Medusans.
没人做到过
No one has.
我指的是我尝试过与其他物种的心灵连接
I was referring to mind-links I had attempted with other species.
我听说你拒绝了和大使的工作
I've heard that you turned down the assignment with the ambassador.
我无法接受，我的使命在这里
I was unable to accept. My life is here.
我们到大使的住处了
We have arrived at the ambassador's quarters.
谢谢，通知所有人员返回岗位
Thank you. Notify all hands to return to stations.
- 我们出发吧，曲速2  - 曲速2，长官
- Let's take her out. Warp factor 2. - Warp factor 2, sir.
我希望有机会向大使问好
I would appreciate an opportunity to greet the ambassador.
我相信大使会被迷住的
I'm sure the ambassador would be charmed.
我几乎要嫉妒你的工作了
I almost envy you your assignment.
我在你的脑海中看到你很想取代我的位置
I see in your mind that you are tempted to take my place.
不准确，博士
Not correct, Doctor.
尽管我意识到你的思想试图与我的思想联系
Although I am aware of your mind attempting to contact mine.
你生来就是心灵感应者吗？
Were you born a telepath?
是的，这就是为什么我必须在瓦肯星上学习
Yes. That is why I had to study on Vulcan.
我明白，我可以带你去你的住处吗？
I understand. May I show you to your quarters?
我想我要在这里待一会儿
I think I'll stay here a bit.
科洛斯大使经常觉得传送过程令人不安
Ambassador Kollos often finds the process of transport unsettling.
我明白，我们船上的外科医生也经常这样抱怨
I understand. Our ship's surgeon often makes the same complaint.
准备好之后呼叫我
Do call when you are ready.
当他看着你时，他看到了什么？
What is it he sees when he looks at you?
我必须知道
I must know.
我不明白他们为什么让你和科洛斯一起去
I can't understand why they let you go with Kollos.
他们？
They?
联邦的男性人口
The male population of the Federation.
难道没有人试图说服你放弃吗？
Didn't someone try and talk you out of it?
既然你问了，是的
Now you ask, yes.
我很高兴他没有，否则你不会在这里
I'm glad he didn't. You wouldn't be here.
谢谢你
Thank you.
为什么你和科洛斯在一起就不危险呢？史波克我能理解
Why isn't it dangerous for you to be with Kollos? Spock I can understand.
- 谢谢你，舰长  - 不客气
- Thank you, Captain. - You're very welcome.
据我所知，没有人可以看着科洛斯不发疯
As I understand it, no human can look at Kollos without going mad.
我花了四年时间在瓦肯星进行心智训练
I spent four years on Vulcan studying mental discipline.
- 可怜的姑娘  - 正相反
- You poor girl. - On the contrary.
我会说琼斯博士确实很幸运
I would say Dr. Jones was indeed fortunate.
- 瓦肯星不如我想的有趣  - 喜悦可以是很多东西，博士
- Vulcan is not my idea of fun. - Joy can be many things, Doctor.
我学会了在其他地方无法学到的东西
I learnt to do things impossible to learn anywhere else.
- 读取想法？ - 如何不去读取想法，舰长
- To read minds? - How not to read them, Captain.
- 我不明白  - 琼斯博士生来就是心灵感应者
- I don't understand. - Dr. Jones was born a telepath.
瓦肯式思维对我的理智来说是必要的
Vulcan was necessary to my sanity.
大多数人发现无法理解的是
What most humans find impossible to understand
将人们的想法和情感拒之门外的需要
is the need to shut out the bedlam of people's thoughts and emotions.
或者他们自己的想法和情感
Or of their own thoughts and emotions.
我刚刚才注意到你的瓦肯IDIC勋章
I was just noticing your Vulcan IDIC.
这是否提醒着，作为瓦肯人
Is it a reminder that as a Vulcan
你能比我更好地与美杜莎人进行心灵连接？
you can mind-link with the Medusans better than I could?
我怀疑史波克先生戴上最受尊敬的瓦肯勋章
I doubt that Mr. Spock would don the most revered of Vulcan symbols
只是为了惹恼你，琼斯博士
merely to annoy you, Dr. Jones.
事实上，我今晚戴它是为了向你致敬，博士
As a matter of fact, I wear it this evening to honor you, Doctor.
的确
Indeed.
有意思，我甚至可以说很吸引人，但说回你的任务
Interesting. I might even say fascinating. But back to your mission.
有没有办法在星舰上雇佣美杜莎导航员？
Can a way be found to employ Medusan navigators on starships?
- 它会解决我们的问题  - 关键是瓦肯心灵连接
- It would solve our problems. - The key is the Vulcan mind-link.
一旦我们与美杜莎人形成了联合智慧体
Once we have formed a corporate intelligence with the Medusans,
像拉里一样的设计师就可以致力于适配仪器了
the designers, like Larry, can work on adapting instruments.
我不在乎美杜莎人有多仁慈
I don't care how benevolent the Medusans are.
和丑到让人发疯的东西打交道难道不是自杀吗？
Isn't it suicidal to deal with something ugly enough to drive men mad?
我看你仍然赞同古希腊人的观念
I see you still subscribe to the notion promulgated by the ancient Greeks
好的东西也必须是美丽的
that what is good must also be beautiful.
反之，美丽的东西自然会被认为是好的
And the reverse. What is beautiful is automatically expected to be good.
我们大多数人都被美丽所吸引，对丑陋排斥
Most of us are attracted by beauty, repelled by ugliness.
冒着听起来有偏见的风险，先生们，敬美丽的人
At the risk of sounding prejudiced, gentlemen, here's to beauty.
敬米兰达·琼斯，有史以来星舰上最可爱的人类
To Miranda Jones, the loveliest human ever to grace a starship.
一个如此美丽的人，怎么能迫使自己永远看丑陋呢？
How can one so beautiful condemn herself to look upon ugliness forever?
- 我们会允许它发生吗？ - 当然不会
- Will we allow it? - Certainly not.
像你这样充满欢乐怎么能
How can one so full of joy as you
迫使自己在余生中看着疾病和痛苦呢？
condemn yourself to look upon disease and suffering for the rest of your life?
我们会允许它发生吗，先生们？
Can we allow that, gentlemen?
敬你最想要的，米兰达
To whatever you want the most, Miranda.
再来点安塔瑞安白兰地？
Some more Antarean brandy?
那是什么？
What is it?
附近有人在想谋杀的事
There's somebody nearby thinking of murder.
- 这个房间里？ - 现在走了
- In this room? - It's gone now.
是谁？你能看出来吗？
Who is it? Can you tell?
它不在了
It isn't there anymore.
- 你介意我说晚安吗？ - 我送你到你的宿舍
- Would you mind if I said goodnight? - I'll see you to your quarters.
谢谢，先生们，你做出了一个不可能的选择
Thank you, gentlemen. You make a choice impossible.
请待在这里玩得开心
Please, stay and enjoy yourselves.
- 这是一顿愉快的晚餐  - 睡个好觉，米兰达
- It was a delightful dinner. - Sleep well, Miranda.
你自己能找到路吗？
Are you well enough to find your way alone?
当然，请不要担心我
Of course. Please don't worry about me.
在我的家乡，我们称之为淑女
Where I come from, that's what we call a lady.
- 她很特别  - 非常特别
- She is something special. - Very special.
我建议你也这样对待她
I suggest you treat her accordingly.
我认识她很久了，我知道她非凡的天赋
I've known her long enough to be aware of her remarkable gifts.
今天对我来说是漫长的一天
Well, it's been a long day for me.
你愿意和我一起在轮机部停一下吗？
Would you like to stop off at engineering with me?
我有几件事要检查
I have a few things to check.
一瓶苏格兰威士忌说你无法处理你设计的控件
A bottle of Scotch says you can't handle the controls you designed.
- 下次吧  - 晚安，先生们
- Some other time. - Goodnight, gentlemen.
为这个场合特意打扮了？非常令人印象深刻
Dressed up for the occasion? Very impressive.
我是真心想向她致敬
I genuinely intended to honor her.
- 晚上好，先生们  - 晚上好，睡个好觉。
- Good evening, gentlemen. - Good evening. Sleep well.
- 这个女孩有什么让你烦恼的？ - 她不是普通的女孩
- What's troubling you with the girl? - She's not just another girl.
- 别犯那种错误  -我没那么想
- Don't make that mistake. - I didn't think that.
我不知道它到底是什么，她似乎非常脆弱
I don't know what it is exactly. She seems very vulnerable.
在某种程度上我们都很脆弱
We're all vulnerable in one way or another.
当然，但她身上有一些非常令人不安的东西
Of course. But there's something very disturbing about her.
说明她是个十足的女人，我同意
Meaning she's quite a woman. I agree.
- 晚安，吉姆  - 晚安，老骨头
- Goodnight, Jim. - Goodnight, Bones.
[门铃声]
[DOOR BUZZES]
男：米兰达？
MAN: Miranda?
- 是谁？ - 拉里，我得和你谈谈
- Who is it? - Larry. I've got to talk to you.
- 很晚了  - 拜托，这一点很重要
- It's late. - Please. It's important.
好的，那进来吧
All right. Come in, then.
我以为晚餐永远不会结束了
I thought the dinner was never going to end.
我倒是很享受
I rather enjoyed it.
是的，我知道你很享受
Yes, I know you did.
我没有，你离得那么远
I didn't. You were so far away.
- 我很快就会离得更远  - 请不要提它
- I'll be further away than that soon. - Please don't talk of that.
时间太少了请，米兰达，不要和科洛斯一起走
There's so little time. Please, Miranda. Don't go with Kollos.
我们已经一次又一次地讨论过这个问题了
We've been over this time and time again.
我难道不知道吗？
Don't I know.
我问过你了，在餐馆里，在实验室里，单膝跪地，双膝跪地
I've asked you in restaurants, in the laboratory, on one knee, both knees.
- 你怎么能这样做？ - 请试着理解
- How can you do this? - Please, try to understand.
我明白，你是女人，我是男人，你的同类之一
I understand. You're a woman, and I'm a man, one of your own kind.
科洛斯永远不会给你这样的东西
Kollos will never give you anything like this.
- 为什么我会遇见你？ - 我一直对你诚实
- Why did I ever meet you? - I've been honest with you.
我只是不能像你希望的那样爱你
I simply cannot love you the way you want me to.
米兰达
Miranda.
我要和科洛斯一起离开，就这么定了
And I'm going away with Kollos. That's final.
我想你最好现在离开
I think you'd better leave now.
所以，是你
So it's you.
之前我不知道是你
I didn't know that it was you before.
你想杀谁？我吗？
Who is it you want to kill? Is it me?
你不能把这件事藏在心里
You mustn't keep this to yourself.
- 我想要帮你  - 现在你想帮我了？
- I want to help you. - So now you want to help me?
现在我知道一个普通人要做什么才能得到你的回应了
Now I know what a mere human has to do to get a reaction out of you.
让你觉得他是个病人
Make you think he's a patient.
伟大的心理学家，你为什么不试着改变一下做一个女人呢？
A great psychologist. Why don't you try being a woman for a change?
斯科特先生在哪里？
Where's Mr. Scott?
米兰达？
Miranda?
所以你忍不住要打一个小赌？
So you couldn't resist a wee wager?
大使受伤了吗？
Has the ambassador been hurt?
- 他没有受到任何伤害  - 谁干的？
- No harm has come to him. - Who could have done it?
拉里·马维克
Larry Marvick.
拉里·马维克？为什么？
Larry Marvick? Why?
他看到美杜莎了吗？
Did he see the Medusan?
- 是的，他看到了  - 那么结果就是精神错乱
- Yes, he did. - Then insanity will be the result.
危险的精神错乱
Dangerous insanity.
你来接管
The controls are all yours.
如果你处理得好，苏格兰威士忌就会在你的房间里
The Scotch will be in your room if you handle them.
柯克舰长呼叫所有船员，红色警报
Captain Kirk to all ship personnel. Red Alert.
有人企图谋杀科洛斯
An attempt was made to murder Kollos.
凶手是个疯子
The murderer is insane.
他是劳伦斯·马维克，留意他，通话完毕
He is Lawrence Marvick. Watch for him. Kirk out.
[碰撞]
[CRASH]
解释一下，苏鲁上尉？
Explain, Lieutenant Sulu?
真不敢相信，但我们正在以曲速8.5飞行
I don't believe this, but we're traveling warp factor 8.5.
- 并且还在加速  - 接轮机部，乌乎拉
- And accelerating. - Get engineering, Uhura.
他们不回答，舰长
They don't answer, Captain.
曲速9，还在加速
Warp factor 9 and accelerating.
你不能从那里解除动力吗？
Can't you disengage power from there?
我正在努力
I'm trying.
契科夫先生，请你协助。
Mr. Chekov, your assistance, please.
- 现在接通轮机部了  - 接入内部通话系统
- I have engineering now. - Put them on intercom.
马维克： 我们决不能睡觉！他们会进入你的梦中！这是最糟糕的
MARVICK: We mustn't sleep! They come into your dreams! That's the worst.
- 我们要离开这里了  - 警卫部到轮机部去
- We're making it out of here. - Security to engineering.
- 我跟你一起走  - 不
- I'll go with you. - No.
我必须去，我能接触到他的思想
I must. I can reach his mind.
我们在宇宙的边界上将是安全的，我们将是安全的！
We'll be safe on the boundaries of the universe. We'll be safe!
- 斯科提，我们在哪儿？ - 我不知道
- Scotty, where are we? - I don't know.
超越银河系的边界，我们做到了，我们安全了
Beyond the boundaries of the galaxy. We made it. We're safe.
我们很安全，柯克舰长
We're safe, Captain Kirk.
老骨头
Bones.
不，不，舰长，我们不能睡觉，不，不
No. No, Captain. We mustn't sleep. No. No.
他们进入你的梦中，在你的梦中使你窒息
They come in your dreams. They suffocate in your dreams.
好的，我们会带你到一个地方躲起来
All right. We'll take you to a place to hide.
- 来吧  - 不，我想留在这里
- Come on. - No, I want to stay here.
准备加速！加速前往下一个星系！
Ready to speed! Speed to the next galaxy!
米兰达
Miranda.
米兰达，你来了，与我一起
Miranda, you're here. With me.
是的，拉里
Yes, Larry.
我在这
I'm here.
我没有失去你，我美丽的爱人，我以为我失去了你
I didn't lose you. My beautiful love, I thought I'd lost you.
我在这里，拉里
I am here, Larry.
不，我能看到他看到的，不，不要
No. I can see what he sees. No, don't.
- 别去想它  - 骗子，骗子
- Don't think of it. - Liar. Liar.
骗子，你不是一个人，它在这里
Deceiver. You're not alone. It's here.
你把它带来了！骗子！骗子！
You brought it with you! Liar! Liar!
骗子！
Liar!
不要爱她！不要爱她！如果你爱她，她会杀了你！
Don't love her! Don't love her! She'll kill you if you love her!
我爱你，米兰达
I love you, Miranda.
他死了，吉姆
He's dead, Jim.
柯克：舰长日志，星历5630.8
KIRK: Captain's log, stardate 5630.8.
由于马维克疯狂的恐惧
As a result of Marvick's insane fears,
企业号被遗弃在未知的太空中
the Enterprise lies derelict in uncharted space.
我们无法确定我们在银河系中的位置
We have no way to determine our position in the galaxy.
我们处于一个完全未知的空白地带
We are in a completely unknown void.
- 我们在哪？ - 从缺乏参照物的情况来看
- Where are we? - Evidently far outside our own galaxy,
显然远在我们的星系之外
judging from the lack of reference points.
当我们超过曲速9.5时，我们进入了一个时空连续体
When we exceeded warp speed 9.5, we entered a space-time continuum.
我有马维克的尸检报告
I have the autopsy report on Marvick.
心跳停止，原因不明
Heart action stop, cause unknown,
呼吸停止，原因不明，脑...
respiration stop, cause unknown, brain...
- 要我继续吗？ - 你是说他就这么死了？
- Shall I go on? - You mean he just simply died?
- 他无法忍受他所看到的  - 或者他感受到的
- He could not live with what he saw. - Or what he felt.
损坏报告
Damage report.
我们需要一些修理，但船是完整的
We need some repairs but the ship is intact.
- 位置报告  - 无法计算
- Position report. - Impossible to calculate.
我们缺乏可供分析的数据，仪器工作正常
We lack data to analyze. Instruments are functioning normally
但现实的东西没有意义
but what they tell us makes no sense.
我们的记录清楚地记下了我们离开我们星系的地方
Our records are clear to the point where we left our galaxy.
我们应该能够导航回去
We should be able to navigate back.
我们缺乏返回的参考点
We lack reference points for returning.
我们经历了感官失真，如果我们使用曲速，还会这样
We experienced sensory distortion, and will do again if we use warp speed.
我们无法重新穿过障碍
We cannot recross the barrier.
一个疯子让我们陷入了这个境地，现在看起来只有疯子才能让我们脱身
A madman got us into this, and it looks like only a madman can get us out.
一个有趣的建议，契科夫先生，但没什么帮助
An entertaining suggestion, Mr. Chekov, but not very helpful.
船上有个人兴许能帮我们导航
There is someone else aboard who might be able to help us navigate.
美杜莎人已经将航海技术发展为一门艺术
The Medusans have developed navigation to a fine art.
感官失真的情况下科洛斯还能正常工作吗？
Could Kollos function despite the sensory distortion?
可能吧，美杜莎的感官系统与我们的完全不同
Possibly. The Medusan sensory system is radically different from ours.
也许为了应对这个紧急情况，我可以成为科洛斯
Perhaps for the purpose of this emergency, I might become Kollos.
- 解释一下  - 融合
- Explain. - A fusion.
创建双重实体的心灵连接
A mind-link to create a double entity.
每个人都会享受两者的知识和感官能力
Each would enjoy the knowledge and sensory capabilities of both.
- 我们将作为一个整体运作  - 风险呢？
- We will function as one being. - Hazards?
如果连接成功，将有失去独立身份的倾向
If the link is successful, there will be a tendency to lose separate identity.
不得不承担的风险
A necessary risk.
琼斯博士不会希望允许我
Dr. Jones will not wish to give me permission
完成心灵链接
to accomplish the mind-link.
我认为她不会希望任何人干涉她与科洛斯的关系
I don't think she'll want anyone to intrude in her rapport with Kollos.
每次我要求与科洛斯交谈时，她都表现出不情愿
She has shown reluctance every time I've asked to converse with Kollos.
在某些方面，她仍然是个凡人，舰长
In some ways, she is still most human, Captain,
尤其是她的嫉妒心
particularly in the depth of her jealousy.
- 我可以把她关在宿舍里  - 那不够
- I could confine her to quarters. - Not sufficient.
她的心灵感应能力很强大
Her telepathic powers are formidable.
她的注意力必须非常投入，我所做的一切才不会惊动她
Her mind must be so engaged that no thought of what I do shall intrude.
我觉得那可以做到
I think that could be arranged.
也许是我多愁善感了，但这是我最喜欢的地方，地球
I may be sentimental, but this is my favorite place. Earth.
我从未去过地球
I've never been to Earth.
多么可爱的花朵
What lovely flowers.
- 我可以碰它们吗？ - 当然
- May I touch them? - Certainly.
他们没有气味
They have no scent.
试试这些
Try these.
让我看看
Let me see.
它只是一根刺
It's just a thorn.
我希望今天能让你忘记这件事
I was hoping to make you forget about this today.
不痛了
It doesn't hurt any more.
你不能责怪自己，因为马维克爱你
You mustn't blame yourself because Marvick loved you.
我不想要他的爱，我无以回报
I didn't want his love. I couldn't return it.
总有一天，你会想要人类的爱和陪伴
Someday, you'll want human love and companionship.
我可以告诉你人类的陪伴对我意味着什么吗？
Shall I tell you what human companionship means to me?
一种挣扎，对他人情感的防御
A struggle. A defense against the emotions of others.
有时，情绪会突然涌上我的心头
At times, the emotions burst in on me.
仇恨，欲望，嫉妒
Hatred, desire, envy.
同情，同情是最糟糕的
Pity. Pity is the worst of all.
我同意瓦肯人的观点
I agree with the Vulcans.
暴力情绪是一种精神错乱
Violent emotion is a kind of insanity.
你愿意与美杜莎人共度一生
You're willing to spend your life
来避免感情用事？
with the Medusans in order to avoid emotion?
也许吧
Perhaps.
情投意合是很好，但是爱呢？
A meeting of minds is all very well, but what about love?
你年轻
You're young.
有魅力，有人性
Attractive. And human.
迟早，不管他们的心灵多么美好
Sooner or later, no matter how beautiful their minds are,
你会渴望一个长得像你的人
you're going to yearn for someone who looks like yourself,
一个不丑的人
someone who isn't ugly.
丑？什么是丑？
Ugly? What is ugly?
谁能说科洛斯是丑得无法忍受？
Who is to say whether Kollos is too ugly to bear?
还是美得无法忍受？
Or too beautiful to bear?
米兰达，我无意冒犯，拜托
Miranda, I meant no insult. Please.
我们置身于玫瑰中，非常浪漫的环境
Here we are among the roses. A very romantic setting.
我希望还有月光
I wish there were moonlight too.
月光会很适合你
Moonlight would suit you very well.
我知道你是个很复杂的人
I see you're a very complicated man.
- 科洛斯，你不能让他这样做  - 别
- Kollos, you mustn't let him do it. - Don't.
让我走，你不知道史波克正在计划着多么危险的事情
Let me go. You have no idea what a dangerous thing Spock is planning.
我们必须阻止他，让我走！
We must stop him. Let me go!
企业号处于危险之中，你不能被卷入
The Enterprise is at stake. It is not possible for you to be involved.
为什么？我承诺会进行心灵连接
Why? I've committed myself to mind-link
当我们接近美杜莎船只时
when we reach the Medusan vessel.
- 为什么要让自己处于危险中？ - 这不是你可以承担的责任
- Why put yourself in jeopardy? - This is not a duty you can assume.
我知道你的心灵感应能力可能比我强
I know your telepathic competence might be superior to mine
但还有一个更重要的因素
but there's a more important factor.
目标是驾驶这艘船，那是你做不到的
The object is to pilot this ship. That is something you cannot do.
教我操作这艘船，我可以瞬间记住
Teach me to operate the ship. I can memorize instantly.
等一下，我意识到你几乎可以做任何有视力的人能做到的事情
Wait a minute. I realize you can do almost anything a sighted person can.
但是你不能驾驶一艘星舰
But you can't pilot a starship.
什么？
What?
真有趣
Fascinating.
对不起，但你必须现实一点
I'm sorry, but you must be realistic.
你是盲人，有些事情你根本做不到
You are blind. There are some things you simply cannot do.
显然是一个高度复杂的传感器网络
Evidently a highly sophisticated sensor web.
我向你和你的裁缝师致敬
My compliments to you and to your dressmaker.
当然，这是唯一合理的解释
Of course. It's the only reasonable explanation.
你看不见，所以科洛斯伤不了你
You can't see and Kollos can't hurt you.
一个优雅的解决方案
An elegant solution.
但我不明白你为什么要隐瞒你的失明
But I fail to understand why you try to conceal your blindness.
我觉得我明白了
I think I understand.
你说同情是最糟糕的
You said that pity is the worst of all.
我讨厌同情
Pity. Which I hate.
你认为你用眼睛得到的信息
Do you think you get more information with your eyes
比我用传感器更多吗？
than I do with my sensors?
我可以和你一起打网球，柯克舰长，我甚至可能打败你
I could play tennis with you, Captain Kirk. I might even beat you.
我正好站在离门1.04米的地方
I am standing exactly one meter four centimeters from the door.
你能那么精确地判断距离吗？
Can you judge distance that accurately?
我甚至可以告诉你你的心跳有多快
I can even tell you how fast your heart is beating.
那没有必要
That won't be necessary.
史波克先生将进行心灵连接，没有其他决定
Mr. Spock will make the mind-link. No other decision is possible.
不，我不会让你这么做的
No. I won't let you.
求你了
Please.
不要像这样反抗我们，琼斯博士
Do not fight us like this, Dr. Jones.
我以同事的身份向你发出呼吁，不要阻挠我们
I appeal to you as a colleague. Do not oppose us.
- 不 - 如果我们不能说服你
- No. - If we can't persuade you,
有人可以
there is someone who can.
你得和科洛斯一起解决这个问题
You'll have to take this up with Kollos.
为你自己着想
For your own sake.
老骨头，你为什么不告诉我？
Bones, why hadn't you told me?
如果她想让你知道，她会告诉你的，我尊重她的隐私
She would have told you if she wanted you to know. I respect her privacy.
这位女士有很多值得尊敬的地方
There's a great deal to respect about that lady.
[尖叫]
[SCREAM]
看来我别无选择，只能听你的了
It seems I have no choice but to obey you.
柯克：舰长日志，补充
KIRK: Captain's log, supplementary.
我们返回银河系的唯一机会
Our one chance to return to our galaxy
取决于美杜莎大使的
is dependent upon the navigational skills
导航技能
of the Medusan ambassador.
科洛斯已被带到舰桥，并被放置在防护罩后面
Kollos has been brought to the bridge and placed behind a protective shield.
这是令人愉快的
This is delightful.
我认识你们所有人
I know you. All of you.
詹姆斯·柯克，舰长和多年的朋友
James Kirk, captain and friend for many years.
还有伦纳德·麦考伊， [大笑] 也认识很久了
And Leonard McCoy. [LAUGHS] Also of long acquaintance.
还有乌乎拉，她名字的意思是自由
And Uhura, whose name means freedom.
她走在美的光彩中，像夜晚
She walks in beauty like the night.
- 那不是史波克  - 你对我读过拜伦感到惊讶吗？
- That's not Spock. - You're surprised I've read Byron?
那是史波克
That's Spock.
我是在向大使讲话吗？
Am I addressing the ambassador?
在某种程度上，我们的一部分被你们称为科洛斯
In part. Part of us is known to you as Kollos.
你在这啊
There you are.
哦，勇敢的新世界，里面有这样的生物
Oh, brave new world, that has such creatures in it.
这对你来说是新鲜的
'Tis new to thee.
我的世界是我们的下一个目标
My world is next for us.
我代表所有美杜莎人讲话，很抱歉给你带来了麻烦
I speak for all of us you call Medusans. Sorry for the trouble I've caused you.
我们没有责怪你，现在感谢您的帮助
We don't hold you to blame. Thank you now for your help.
现在谈谈手头的正事
And now to the business at hand.
- 得到你的许可，舰长  - 让史波克先生掌舵
- With your permission, Captain. - Release the helm to Mr. Spock.
是的，长官
Aye, sir.
- 协调已完成  - 那就出发，史波克先生
- Coordination is completed. - Then go ahead, Mr. Spock.
6秒内达到曲速1
Warp 1 in six seconds.
五四三二一...
Five, four, three, two, one...
零
Zero.
[引擎嗡嗡声]
[ENGINE HUMS]
请位置报告
Position report, please.
我们的位置？
Our position?
我们的位置非常接近我们进入虚空的点
Our position is so close to the point where we entered the void,
差异不值得一提
the difference isn't worth mentioning.
- 正中靶心！  - 谢谢
- Bull's-eye! - Thank you.
- 操作完成  - 苏鲁先生接手
- Maneuver completed. - Take over, Mr. Sulu.
谢谢大使， 契科夫先生，绘制一条新航线
Thank you, Ambassador. Mr. Chekov, plot a new course.
新航向将在一分钟内绘制完毕
New headings will be plotted in a minute.
你们的躯体多么结实啊
How compact your bodies are.
你们有多么多样的感官
What a variety of senses you have.
不过，你们称之为语言的东西
This thing you call language, though.
最了不起，你们非常依赖它
Most remarkable. You depend on it for so very much.
但是你们当中有人真的是它的主人吗？
But is any one of you really its master?
但最重要的是，孤独感
But most of all, the aloneness.
你们是如此孤独
You are so alone.
你们在这个……肉体中度过你的一生
You live out your lives in this... shell of flesh.
独立的，分开的
Self-contained. Separate.
你们是多么的孤独啊
How lonely you are.
多么的孤独
How terribly lonely.
大使？
Ambassador?
您必须解除连接
You must dissolve the link.
这么快？
So soon?
绝不能拖延
There must be no delay.
你是个明智的舰长
You're a wise captain.
史波克！别看！捂住眼睛！
Spock! Don't look! Cover your eyes!
[史波克大喊]
[SPOCK SHOUTS]
- 别动，所有人都别动  - 吉姆
- Don't move. No one is to move. - Jim.
史波克？
Spock?
你没事吧？
Are you all right?
史波克？
Spock?
没事了，你现在和我们在一起很安全
It's all right. You're safe with us now.
他几乎没有呼吸，帮我把他送到医务室
He's hardly breathing. Help me get him to Sickbay.
除非米兰达能洞察他的想法并将其转达给我们，否则我们将失去史波克
Unless Miranda can look into his mind and turn it to us, we'll lose Spock.
瓦肯人的心智技术显得如此不可信，现在他的生命受到威胁
Vulcan mind techniques seem so untrustworthy now his life is at stake.
她对他们的了解是唯一可以拯救他的理智
Her knowledge of them is the only thing that could save his sanity,
或生命的东西
or his life.
但她愿意吗？
But does she want to?
- 她在那里待了这么久  - 没别的办法了
- She's been in there so long. - There's nothing else to be done.
- 她试图帮助马维克，结果他死了  - 那不一样，他爱她
- She tried to help Marvick. He's dead. - That's different. He loved her.
而史波克是她的对手，这有什么好处吗？
And Spock is her rival. Is that any better?
史波克感受到了她嫉妒的暴力
Spock felt the violence of her jealousy.
他们不是情敌
They weren't rivals in love.
吉姆...
Jim...
- 你不应该进去  - 无论发生什么，都不要干涉
- You shouldn't go in there. - Whatever happens, don't interfere.
是谁？麦考伊博士？
Who is it? Dr. McCoy?
谁在那儿？
Who's there?
柯克舰长
Captain Kirk.
我没有消息要告诉你，舰长
I have no news for you, Captain.
没变化？
No change?
只知道他的生命过程正在衰退
Only that his life processes are ebbing.
- 你在做什么？ - 当然是我能做的
- What are you doing about it? - What I can, of course.
然而似乎并不多
Which doesn't seem to be much.
你觉得我可以用一个吻唤醒他吗？
You think I can wake him with a kiss?
值得一试，他不是机器
Worth a try. He's not a machine.
但他是瓦肯人
But he is a Vulcan.
半人，显然比你多
Half human. More than you, apparently.
面对现实吧，舰长
Face reality, Captain.
他的思维已经微弱到连我都几乎难以触及了
His mind has gone down almost too far even for me to reach.
如果你不尽快找到他，他就会死
If you don't reach him soon, he'll die.
- 但这就是你想要的，不是吗？ - 才不是
- But that's what you want, isn't it? - That's a lie.
你想让他死，你让他忘记戴面罩了吗？
You want him to die. Did you make him forget to put on his visor?
- 你疯了  - 你了解你的对手，不是吗？
- You're insane. - You know your rival, don't you?
你不能阻止他建立你做不到的心灵连接
You couldn't keep him from making a mind-link, something you couldn't do.
用我的话说，我会让你听到那样的丑陋
With my words, I'll make you hear such ugliness.
史波克用他的肉眼看到的丑陋……丑陋在你的心中
What Spock saw with his naked eyes... The ugliness is within you.
- 不是的！骗子！  - 你想见科洛斯的愿望是疯狂的
- That's a lie! Liar! - Your desire to see Kollos is madness.
你永远都见不到他，永远！
You can never see him, never!
但是史波克看到了科洛斯，为此，他必须死
But Spock saw Kollos. And for that, he must die.
虐待狂，肮脏的骗子！
Sadistic, filthy liar!
嫉妒的恶臭弥漫在你身上，你为什么不掐死他？
The stench of jealousy permeates you. Why don't you strangle him?
- 别再说了！ - 科洛斯知道你内心的想法
- Don't say any more! - Kollos knows what's in your heart.
- 你可以骗自己，但不能骗他  - 请走开
- You can lie to yourself but not to him. - Please go away.
- 你对她说了什么？ - 也许太多了
- What did you say to her? - Maybe too much.
- 她在里面做什么？ - 也许我不应该进去
- What's she doing in there? - Maybe I shouldn't have gone in.
她是瞎子，真的很瞎，真的处于黑暗中
She was blind, really blind, really in the dark.
如果他死了，我怎么知道我没有杀了他？
And if he dies, how do I know that I didn't kill him?
我怎么知道她能忍受听到真相？
How do I know that she can stand to hear the truth?
现在，史波克，这对我们俩来说
Now, Spock. This is to the death,
都是死亡，或者说是生命
or to life for both of us.
你看起来像是拜访了魔鬼本人
You look like you've paid a visit to the devil himself.
- 你有你最想要的东西吗？ - 我和科洛斯是一体的
- You have what you wanted most? - I am at one with Kollos.
真遗憾你要走了，再见
I'm truly sorry that you're leaving. Goodbye.
我们结束了一次多事的旅行，舰长
We come to the end of an eventful trip, Captain.
- 我没想到你会跟我说话  - 为了我的未来，我要感谢你
- I didn't think you'd talk to me. - I have you to thank for my future.
你的话让我能够看到了
Your words enabled me to see.
米兰达，祝你好运，健康，我有东西给你
Miranda, good luck. Health. I have something for you.
我猜它有刺
I suppose it has thorns.
我从没遇到过没有刺的玫瑰
I never met a rose that didn't.
我现在知道你和科洛斯的心灵连接时所感受到的巨大喜悦了
I know now the great joy you felt when you joined minds with Kollos.
我为你的知识和成就感到高兴
I rejoice in your knowledge and in your achievement.
我明白，史波克先生
I understand, Mr. Spock.
创造的繁荣在于其无限的多样性
The glory of creation is in its infinite diversity.
以及我们的差异相结合来创造意义和美的方式
And the ways our differences combine to create meaning and beauty.
- 安居乐业，长盛不衰，史波克  - 生生不息，繁荣昌盛，米兰达
- Peace and long life, Spock. - Live long and prosper, Miranda.
安居乐业
Peace.